So, here's what happens when you come to
our restaurants. We ask you if you've
been here before. If you say no, we put
a red cocktail napkin down. Everybody
else has a white napkin, you got a red
napkin. You say, "Why do I have a red
napkin?" You're a new customer. We want
to make sure we welcome you. Oh, that
feels pretty good. A manager must come
up, introduce himself. We'll send you a
postcard that says you can get a free
rib dinner at my restaurant any day of
the week. Nobody with you, no
restrictions at all. So, you come to my
restaurant, you put the red napkin down,
you give me the card for the free rib
dinner. You have your free rib dinner.
Other people spend $1,000 on media to
get a customer to come to their bar.
Costs me $4 and a rib dinner. At the end
of the rib dinner, just as it's ending,
the manager comes up to the table, says,
"Hey, how was your ribs?" Oh, man, they
were delicious. You got to try
our chicken. He writes on the back of a
business card, $5 off chicken, gives it
to you. Now, the manager's your buddy.
It's handwritten. You come back with the
business card for the $5 off chicken,
which I'm breaking even on now, so
there's no expense on this one. You put
the card down on the table. Everybody
knows it's your second visit. You get
the chicken dinner, all that. At the end
of the meal, the manager comes over,
says, "How was it?" He goes, "Great."
You follow him. Stop. You got to come
back and try my cheesecake. And he
writes it on the back of the card, free
piece of cheesecake. I get you back for
the third visit. I got a 72% likelihood
of another visit. And here's the trick.
In media, and I hate to say this on a
media platform, but the typical
restaurant in a market like New York, if
you advertise and then look at how many
new customers you get, your acquisition
[music] cost can be almost $1,200 for
every customer you get. It costs
me $4 for a rib dinner, [music] a dollar
for the postcard, and a free piece of
cheesecake. The chicken was a wash. So,
costs me about $8 to get a new customer.
Costs somebody else over a thousand. If
you go [music] to a restaurant and have
a flawless experience, I mean, flawless,
the statistical likelihood of you coming
back to that restaurant is about [music]
42%. If you do come back and have a
flawless experience, your statistical
likelihood of coming back a third time
is still under 50%, about 47. But, if
you come back a third time, the
statistical likelihood of a fourth visit
is 72%. Where restaurant tours blow it
is they market to one visit. I market to
three visits. That's the way you market
a restaurant. Isn't that like
mind-blowing?